A Guide to the Slide Collection of Joe Perdue, 1969-1992
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Slide Collection from the Estate of Joe Perdue, 1969-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11444
This collection consists of 1000 (ca.) slides.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
On September 10, 1998 this collection was given from the estate of Joe Perdue through Florence Kabir of White Hall, Va. 22987.
Scope and Content Information
This slide collection consists primarily of wild life and nature scenes in Virginia, North Carolina, and West Virginia.
Of special interest is a series devoted to the effects and repair of the Rockfish River area in Nelson County, Virginia, battered by Hurricane Camille. The slides detail the damage and ecological changes, 1969- 1990, wrought by the hurricane.
Other subjects include the South Pacific, particularly New Zealand and Tahiti; astronomy, particularly the building of an observatory and a 1970 eclipse; animals in the San Diego zoo; and the construction of a small bridge.
Contents List
- Slides, 1973-1992, Ten sets of slides
  - Astronomy, 1973-1986 (Box 1)
    These slides feature a telescope, moon, eclipse, Haley's Comet, sunsets and sunrises.
  - Ecology, 1969-1992 (Box 1)
    These slides feature the damage and repair of Rockfish River, Nelson County after Hurricane Camille.
  - South Pacific, 1977 (Box 1)
    These slides feature scenes from New Zealand and Tahiti, including, flowers, a lagoon, a luau, a drive around the island, Rotarua and Maori artifacts, and Palmerston and Tekapo.
  - Wildflowers, 1970-1984 (Box 1)
    These slides feature the Yorktown onion, trillium, orchid, fox glove, and West Virginia.
  - Wildflowers, 1972-1977 (Box 1)
    These slides feature sassafras, amaryllis, pansies, beebalm, orchid, azalea, sumac, and firepink.
  - Wildflowers, 1972-1984 (Box 2)
    These slides feature butterfly weed, trillium, roses, firepink, bluebells, thistle, and mushrooms.
  - Wildlife, 1970-1984 (Box 2)
    These slides feature moths, woodchuck, hummingbirds, snakes, bugs, a butterfly, ducks, birds, worms, and San Diego Zoo animals.
  - Wilderness, 1977 (Box 2)
    These slides feature flowers, mushrooms and parkway in Boone, North Carolina.
  - Wilderness, 1977 (Box 2)
    These slides feature Grandfather's Mountain in Boone, North Carolina.
  - Wilderness, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    These slides feature Spruce Knob, West Virginia.
- Photographs and Negatives, Three groups of photographs
  - Astronomy
    These photographs feature construction of an observatory, an eclipse, and the Langley Astronomy Club building.
  - Ecology
    These photographs feature Rockfish River flood damage and the construction of a bridge.
  - Wilderness
    These photographs feature Parkway, Rockfish River, and Thunder Ridge.